So, from this session we are going to dump into the security or actual security, how the
attacker will hijack the comp environment without any noise or detections and how they
will operate. We will learn each and everything, okay. So, in the first video we will learn
the stage and stage of the stage, sometimes this will be, this question will be asking
in interviews, if you are a fresh or experienced or any. If you are going for a routine
any, any jobs, okay. I will cover everything, so how to, so which payload is better,
stage are stages, how it will be get caught, okay. So, first one we will going to discuss
the stage payload, okay. So, stage, so let us take a stage payload, okay. So, it will be
delivered by a power, okay. So, first thing, when you download the stage payload, so it
will just give a C2 connection, like it will just give a terminal connection, okay terminal
connection. So, next after getting the terminal connection, so this is the first part, okay.
The second part will be getting uploaded, okay to the target windows, okay. It will be
delivered by one by one, okay. First part, second part, third part. So, if you, if you, if
a payload need to do any other things like current shield on b-card village is patient,
the third part, fourth part it will be, it will be sent it by the part by part, okay.
It will be delivered by the part two part, okay. But if you see the stageless payload,
it will not be delivered by the part two part, okay. It will be delivered by the single
payload, okay. This will not be delivered by the single payload, every, it will be delivered
by one by one part. This will be delivered by a single payload, okay. Everything will be
in the same part. So, you know the stage payload will be actually less when you are generating,
it is less size. So, you will not be get easily caught by antivirus officers or any
idiot platform because this payload only will send a C2 connection, right. The next payload
will do some other tasks, the next payload will do some other tasks, the next payload
will do some other tasks, okay. But stageless is actually not like that, okay. It's pretty
different, okay. So, everything the first, the second, third, fourth, everything will
be delivered in a single file, okay. Single file, okay. Now, the, the file size will be,
big, okay. It's a bigger size. So, anyway, it will be a bigger size. And it will be easily
caught by EDR or antivirus platforms because every payloads are single file, right. Single
file, okay. Let me go and develop that. I will, I will teach you the real time in the practical
field. Let me jump into the, one of the C2 parameter. We will cover these things in later.
So, let's go to the windows, page or payload. So, let's select, hmm. This is a very
example, okay. This is just an example. Don't worry about the tool. We will be learning
this tool in the next section, the cobalt section, okay. Let's develop. I need to give
example what is the stage and stageless, okay. So, that I was covering this tool. Don't
worry about the usage as and don't worry about the working principle of this tool. I will
be covering each and everything in a, a demonstration, okay. Let's select this and we will
generate a payload. So, let me put it in the music directory. So, we will generate a payload
named a stage.exe. So, in the same time, we will generate an stageless payload, okay, stage
less payload. Select a generate, so, stageless, okay. So, I already said, stage will be delivered
by part two part, okay, one by one part, okay. It will be delivered, one by one part, okay.
So, now just go to the properties of a stage payload. You can see there is only a 19 kilobytes
of file. If I go to the stageless, so now you can find the difference between both of the
things, okay. I already discussed, stage payloads will be delivered by part by part, but stage
less payload will be delivered single file. Every payloads will be delivered in a one, one
file. So, you can see the file here two, eight, nine, K, B, and you can see the another file
here, stage to payload. You can see only 19 kilobytes of data will be there, but stage
payload, there is a two, eight in a kilobytes of data, sorry, stageless payload, there
is a two, eight in a kilobytes of data will be there, okay. So, this is the difference between
the stage and stageless payload, okay. So, if you want to go for a payload, which will
be easily bypassed the antivirus software and malware, sorry, malware detection programs.
So, you need to use the stage payload, okay. So, because it will be delivered by one part
by part, okay. Your antivirus software are EDRs. Don't know what what happening and what
was the file is about, okay. So, but if there is a network monitoring, where SARC or if
they are using the where SARC and do a critical network monitoring, okay, the environment,
the organization is doing a very, very good critical things in network monitoring, then
you will be get caught by the stage grid, okay. So, anyway, it will be delivered by part
one, part two, part three, part four, right, right. However, each river where SARC will
resolve everything towards what's ascending and what's receiving, right. So, it will be
get caught by the network monitoring, but it will be bypassing the EDRs and AV sometime,
okay. But stageless, it will not get caught by the where SARC, so we can bypass the
where SARC, but it will be caught by the AV EDRs and other part forms, okay. This is the
difference between both of the things, but the stage will be caught by the where SARC because
payload will be delivered one by one, one first file, second file, third file, fourth file
like that, but stageless, there is a single payload, it will be directly sent to the
target machine. So, there's if there is if they are monitoring the network, so then they
don't know what happening in federal network, because there is only one file, which will
be sent to the target machine, okay. But stageless, stage is not like that, payload will
be sent by one part, one part, second part, third part like that, okay, based on direct
command. This difference between the stage and stageless payload, so you can use both
EDRs, stageless, stageless for a C2 connections, but in this course I will be mostly
using the stage payload for doing many attacks, okay. So, I hope you have clear understanding
about the stage and stageless payload, once again stage payload will be delivered by part
by part, but stageless payload will be delivered by a single file, so that's the difference,
you can see your size will be less in stage and size will be bigger in stageless, okay.
So, let's swap off this video and we will continue our discussion in the next video. See
you guys, bye bye.